A Guide to the Baylor Family Papers 1714-1738 (bulk 1770-1848)
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Baylor Family Papers, 1714-1938, 1770-1848.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 59.1
6 volumes and 54 pieces.
Baylor Family,; Francis Walker Baylor,; John Baylor, Jr.,; George D. Baylor,; Warner Lewis Baylor
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1959.
Alternative Form
Microfilm copy (M-1556) of entire collection and photostats of selected items (PH/04) available.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, primarily 1770-1848, accumulated by members of the Baylor family of New Market, Caroline County, Va., especially Frances Walker Baylor (d. 1783), her son, John Baylor, Jr. (1750-1808), who studied in England ca. 1770-1772, her grandson, Dr. George D. Baylor (1789-1848), and her great grandson, Dr. Warner Lewis Baylor (1825-1894). The loose papers are mainly family letters, legal records, genealogical information, and poems. Manuscript books include a nineteenth-century cookbook, Dr. George D. Baylor's ledger of medical accounts, 1842-1847, and genealogical information on the Lewis and related families. Three printed books have been transferred to the library. The collection is complemented by various photostats, including Col. John Baylor's letterbook, 1749-1765, with letters to John Backhouse, Samuel Waterman, John Norton, Edward Athawes, Cary and Company, and others.
Arrangement
Items are arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Persons:
Baylor, Frances Walker, d.1783.; Baylor, John, 1750-1808.; Baylor, George D., 1789-1848.; Baylor, Warner Lewis, 1835- 1894.; Clay, James.; Farrish, Robert.; Fox, John.; Hoomes, George.; Pendleton, John L.; Powell, Robert.; Taylor, Edmund.; Waring, F.
Family Names:
Baylor family.; Lewis family.
Subjects:
Cookery --Virginia --History --19th century; Medical care --Virginia --History --19th century; Virginia Genealogy
Contents List
- John Baylor - plat for 400 acres. 24 September 1714 (Folder 1)
- John Baylor - court order. 8 April 1743 (Folder 1)
- Robert Powell - Notice to sheriff to apprehend runaway slave belonging to Robert Powell. 13 August 1743 (Folder 1)
- George Hoomes and Robert Farish - Proclamation. Caroline County. 20 August 1743 (Folder 1)
- F. Waring - Coroner's Report. 8 November 1743 (Folder 1)
- Edmund Taylor to Col. J[ohn] Baylor. 15 March 1756 (Folder 1)
- Frances Baylor to John Baylor. 25 May 1770 (Folder 1)
- James Clay to John Baylor. 25 July 1779 (Folder 1)
- Bond. John Baylor to Alex[ander] Spotswood. 24 August 1780 (Folder 1)
- To George Wythe, Judge of the High Court of the Chancery, re the will of John Fox. [1780] (Folder 1)
- Copy of Judgment. William Dickson's Administrator v. George Baylor's Executors. Executed 2 June 1790. 15 May 1790 (Folder 1)
- John Baylor - invoice. 11 February 1800 (Folder 1)
- John Baylor, Jr. to John Baylor. 2 March 1805 (Folder 1)
- John Baylor to George D. Baylor. 1 February 1809 (Folder 1)
- Court Order. Baylor v. Fox. 2 April 1816 (Folder 1)
- Commission for justices of the peace to examine Elizabeth Baylor. Daingerfield v. Rootes. Printed with manuscript inserts. 27 December 1823 (Folder 1)
- Deed of Trust (Clerk's Copy) George D. Baylor to John W. Fox. 31 December 1823 (Folder 1)
- Elizabeth L. Baylor to Ellen Augusta Baylor. 4 November 1831 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor to John Baylor. 30 April 1832 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor to John N. Baylor. 23 May 1835 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor to Benjamin W. Leigh. 21 October 1837 (Folder 2)
- Poem by George D. Baylor. 1 May 1840 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor to George R. Baylor. 30 November 1841 (Folder 2)
- R. H. Kidd to Joseph W. Kay. 27 May 1844 (Folder 2)
- Margaret P. Olivier to Ellen A. Baylor. 14 January 1845 (Folder 2)
- Account. John W. Fox. May, 1845 (Folder 2)
- Statement of money received of John W. Fox. May, 1845 (Folder 2)
- Poem by Mrs. Dunel. 16 August 1845 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor - power of attorney. 14 October 1845 (Folder 2)
- Poem. 20 December 1846 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor to John N. Baylor. 16 January 1848 (Folder 2)
- Poem. [14 February] 1848 (Folder 2)
- Agreement and Sale between Warner L. Baylor and Ellen A. Baylor. 25 March 1848 (Folder 2)
- Julia [B. Kay] to George D, Baylor. 5 [February] 1848 (Folder 2)
- George R. Baylor, statement of money paid. 6 June 1860 (Folder 2)
- Copy of Will of the Honorable Hatley Frere. 5 December 1868 (Folder 2)
- Alexander G. Baylor to Julia B. Kay. 5 June 1872 (Folder 2)
- William Winston Fontaine to Warner L. Baylor. 18 July 1883 (Folder 2)
- George D. Baylor to Warner L. Baylor. N. D. (Folder 2)
- H. T. Deas to G. D. Baylor. 11 August 1938 (Folder 3)
- Despilly, receipted. N. D. (Folder 3)
- Poem by Dr. John C. McCabe. N. D. (Folder 3)
- Poem. N. D. (Folder 3)
- Poem by George D. Baylor. N. D. (Folder 3)
- Poem by George D. Baylor. N. D. (Folder 3)
- Lewis family. 6 April 1891 (Folder 3)
- Baylor Family Information N. D. (Folder 4)
- Biographical sketch by Dr. Warner L. Baylor. N. D. (Folder 4)
- Genealogical material on Lewis Family. N. D. (Folder 4)
- Baylor Family genealogical material. N. D. (Folder 4)
- Frere Family genealogical material, includes a copy of August 12, 1795 letter from I. Frere to Mrs. Baylor. N. D. (Folder 4)
- Lewis Family (Gloucester County, Va.) N. D. (Folder 4)
- Baylor Family genealogical chart. N. D. (Folder 4)
- Baylor Family genealogical chart. N. D. (Folder 4)